A recap of the previous episode.
前情提要
After applying to this high school, we met the genius child actress again.
在申請入學後 我們與天才童星再次相遇了
Are you taking our entertainment course?!
你是來報讀我們演藝科的吧？對吧？
No, I applied for the general course.
不是喔，我報的是一般學科
Why?!
為什麼？
My sister applied for the entertainment course, so I was worried and tagged along.
我家妹妹報考了演藝科 我擔心才報考這裡的
Huh?!
什麼？
My brother has a sister complex.
我家老哥超妹控的
Gross!
好噁！
You know, I've never really liked this girl.
我之前就不是很喜歡這女的了
But if you get in, she's gonna be your senior.
妳要是考上了，就變成她的後輩了
Hmm, I see.
嗯，這樣啊
I can hear you two.
我都聽見了喔
Aww, fine then.
好吧，真是沒辦法
Let's get along, Loli senpai.
我們好好相處吧，蘿莉學姐
I'll really bully you!
小心我霸凌妳喔！
Then I'll be dropping by the director's place.
我先去導演那邊
Okay, bye.
好，掰掰
Oh, wait!
等等！
Hey! I said hey!
喂！我叫你等等！
Where are you going? Who's this director?!
你要去哪？導演是哪個導演？
Hey! Where do you live right now?
喂，你現在住哪裡？
You listening?! I said hey!
你有在聽嗎？喂！
What middle school you from?!
你哪間中學的？
Are you a yankii girl?
這什麼不良少女的問法？
How long are you gonna follow me?
妳是要跟到什麼時候？
Until you answer all of my questions.
跟到你回答完我所有問題
You're still an actor, right?
你現在還是演員吧？
No, not anymore.
不，我沒在演戲了
I-I see…
這樣啊…
So that's that.
就是這樣
Let's chat a little!
再聊一下嘛
Hey! You wanna go to karaoke or something?
那個啊 要不要去卡拉OK之類的地方？
No way.
才不去
Oh. Then… maybe my place?
咦？那…要去我住的地方嗎？
Isn't that closing the distance too fast?
這種拉近距離的速度 不覺得有點不妙嗎？
I can't help it! I am still a celebrity after all!
沒辦法啊！誰叫我姑且算是藝人
I can't just sit down at a café to chat.
又不能在咖啡廳坐著聊天
There are no stores with private rooms open at this time yet!
這時間點有私人包廂的店又還沒開
Oh, that's what you meant.
喔，是這樣啊
If that's the case…
那麼…
Oh, Kana Arima!
哦，有馬佳奈
Haven't seen you in a while, but you've grown!
好一陣子沒看到妳，長這麼大啦
Uh, well…
呃，這個…
I am still working…
我姑且還是有在工作…
Compared to when I was a child actress, I'm not as… you know, but…
雖然相比童星時期 比較沒那麼…但是…
Well, make yourself at home!
隨意點，當自己家啊
I see.
這樣啊
Hey, Aqua.
阿奎亞
If you're not an actor anymore, why are you visiting the director's place?
為什麼你不當演員了 還是跑來導演這裡呢？
You sure you're not really studying acting?
你確定你不是來接受演技指導的嗎？
Well, I was taught everything,
我是有學起來了
but now, I'm like the director's assistant aiming for backstage.
但是現在是以幕後人員為目標 算是在做導演助理
Really.
這樣啊
But I'm glad.
但我很高興
You were still in this industry.
你還在業界這件事
Do you want seconds?!
要再添飯嗎？
Uh, I'm fine. I'm cutting down on sugars.
不用了，我在戒澱粉
If you don't eat, you won't grow!
不吃點東西的話長不高的
-You eat this. -What?!
-你吃吧 -什麼？
Jeez.
真是的
But what a shock.
還真是驚人啊
Huh?
什麼？
Director, I didn't know you were still leeching off your parents.
導演，我都不知道 你到現在還在啃老耶
You're still the same brat that never respects your elders.
妳還是一樣不懂尊重長輩耶
But it's nice.
但也不錯啦
My parents moved back to the countryside, so I live in a dorm alone.
我爸媽搬回鄉下了 我現在自己住在宿舍
So, I usually depend on Uber for meals.
所以吃飯都靠Uber了
Really.
這樣啊
That must be expensive.
那應該很貴吧
I'm fine!
沒問題
Since at least my savings is loaded from when I worked as a child star!
當童星的時候已經賺得荷包飽飽了
I freaking hate you.
妳真的超討人厭
Hey, Director. Don't you have any videos of Aqua acting?
導演，你這裡有 阿奎亞演戲的影片嗎？
Umm, I do, but…
是有啦，但是…
Don't show it.
不准放
I was just delusional and it's an embarrassing past.
那不過是我當時鬼迷心竅的黑歷史
I mistook myself for having talent and made a fool of myself.
就是一部誤以為自己有演戲才能 自欺欺人的作品罷了
You heard him.
妳聽到了
So if you wanna see, you gotta talk this guy into acting yourself.
所以妳要是想看的話 自己哄哄他，叫他表演給妳看吧
Is that how you wanna do it?
還有這招啊？
I'm not doing it.
我才不演呢
Right now, I'm cast as the heroine in this one title,
我現在可是一部劇的女主角
but there's a role that's still open.
但目前有個角色還找不到人選
You want me to talk with the higher-ups?
要我跟高層說說看嗎？
Nope.
不用了
What?!
什麼？
What's the title called?
是哪部戲？
A drama based on a shoujo manga called Mild Flavor Today.
是叫做《今天就稍微甜一點》 少女漫畫改編的連續劇
I see.
這樣啊
Mild Today?
《今甜》？
Yeah, you know it?
對，你知道啊？
Anyone who's studied staging that doesn't know it must live under a rock.
只要研究過分鏡的人 沒有不知道的吧？
It's a masterpiece.
那可是名作耶
So you're interested?
你有興趣了嗎？
I told you I don't act anymore.
就說我沒在演戲了
If I talk to them, it might smoothly go through.
由我來說一下 應該很容易就能拿下角色囉
Since the producer, Mr. Kaburagi, likes me!
誰叫製作人鏑木先生很疼我呢？
Kaburagi?
鏑木？
Is his full name Masaya Kaburagi?
全名是鏑木勝也嗎？
That's right.
是沒錯啦
There are three cell phones Ai left behind.
愛留下來的手機一共有三支
Two of them were for work and private use
一支是工作用，一支是私人用
and only had records of other group members and agency staff.
裡面只有和其他成員 和事務所工作人員的通話紀錄
Ai seemed careless, but she was much more careful than I imagined.
愛看起來粗心大意 其實比我想像中還小心謹慎
I learned that she was seriously trying to hide our secret.
看來她是真心想將我們的事保密
The problem is the other cell phone.
問題是剩下的那支手機
This one was used by Ai before she got pregnant.
這支是愛在懷孕前使用的
It was several generations old,
因為是好幾代以前的手機
so it was backbreaking to find a replacement for the dead battery.
找到型號相符，換掉老舊的電池 費了好大一番功夫
But that was nothing compared to bypassing the passcode.
但跟破解密碼比起來 根本算不了什麼
It's unusable for 30 seconds if I get the passcode wrong
要是密碼輸入錯誤 就會在30秒內無法操作
and I don't even know how many digits it is.
也不知道密碼有幾位數
It took me half a day to try 100 passcodes.
光是試100組密碼就花了我半天
It took me a month for 1,000 attempts.
試1000組密碼花了我一個月
Day after day…
每天不斷嘗試
On the 45,510th attempt…
終於在第45510次…
ENTER YOUR PASSCODE
（輸入密碼）
I finally reached the passcode after four years had passed.
花了整整四年後，將密碼破解了
On that phone,
在那支手機裡面
there were emails and numbers of a dozen of those affiliated in showbiz.
還有十幾位演藝圈相關人士的 郵件地址和手機號碼
And one of them was…
其中一位就是…
Masaya Kaburagi…
鏑木勝也…
Hey, let's try it!
來試試看嘛
Most of the cast are close to our age too.
大部分演員年紀都跟我們差不多
The main boy has a girly face, so he's really cute!
男主角臉長得很像女生，蠻可愛的
-I'll do it. -What?
-我演 -咦？
Call the producer for me.
幫我聯絡製作人吧
Why do you all of a sudden…
為什麼突然答應…
Wait, no way…
什麼？不會吧？
The main boy has a girly face, so he's really cute!
男主角臉長得很像女生，蠻可愛的
Don't tell me you're…
難不成你…
Let's do it.
等著瞧吧
I can't wait to see Aqua's acting.
等不及看阿奎亞演戲了
Oh, but this set has some problems, so be prepared, okay?
但是那片場有點問題 要有心理準備，知道嗎？
Hm?
什麼？
FROM TOKYO
（阿奎亞，出生於東京）
He was a child actor?
童星出身的男孩子？
Yes!
是！
Hmm.
嗯
He's got a pretty face.
臉長得蠻端正的
If you with your strong acting skills speak so highly of him, bring him in.
如果真的像妳說的演技那麼好 那就帶他過來吧
Okay, I'll leave it to you.
好，那就麻煩囉
Is it settled?
敲定了嗎？
Huh? Yeah.
嗯？是啊
Well, I don't care who takes the role anyway.
誰來演其實都無所謂啦
MASAYA KABURAGI
（鏑木勝也）
What? Aqua, you're gonna be in a drama?!
什麼？阿奎亞要出演連續劇了？
Why did you tell her?
妳幹嘛跟她說啦？
Because you would never say anything yourself.
因為你自己絕對不會說的吧？
It's the agency's job to promote the activities of registered artists.
為旗下藝人管理行程 也是事務所的職責之一喔
Mama did say…
媽媽有說過…
that my future might be an idol and Aqua might be a future actor.
我未來會成為偶像 阿奎亞會成為演員
So you never forgot those words.
看來你沒忘記那些話啊
It's not like that.
才不是這樣
If I can meet the producer Ai had interacted with when she was alive
我不過是想遇到 愛生前有過聯繫的製作人
and retrieve the root of his hair, that'll be all I need.
拔下他的頭髮，僅此而已
I'm not thinking of doing anything great like fulfilling Ai's wishes
完成愛的遺願、懷抱對演員的憧憬
or dreaming of becoming an actor.
我才沒有這種高尚的念頭
What's the title of the show?
那部劇叫什麼名字？
The title is Mild Flavor Today. It's based on a shoujo manga.
叫做《今天就稍微甜一點》 少女漫畫改編的
Oh! I know it! Mild Today!
我知道，《今甜》！
It's the one in Aqua's room! It was interesting!
阿奎亞的房間有這部，很有趣耶
Don't read it without asking.
別擅自拿來看啦
It's a drama by a recently established streaming platform.
是由最近才成立的網路電視台製作
Three episodes have already been released out of six.
總共有六集，已經播完三集了
There are many new faces in the main cast.
主演群有很多新面孔
It's a rather small-scale series.
算是比較小規模的作品
Looks like Aqua's role is the bad guy in the last episode.
阿奎亞的角色好像是最後一集的反派
That's perfect. You do have an evil face.
很適合你嘛，畢竟長著一副壞人臉
Shut up.
吵死了
It's a streaming platform's drama, so we can watch it right now.
是網路劇的話，現在就能收看了
I wanna watch!
我想看！
I hate humans.
我討厭人類
Because everyone only thinks about themselves.
因為所有人都只在乎自己的事情
Oh, it's Loli senpai!
是蘿莉學姐
You know,
妳啊
are you even having fun with a face like that?
整天擺著那副表情，很有趣嗎？
What do you want?
你想幹嘛？
Nothing. I just chased after a cat and found you here.
沒什麼，只是追著一隻貓 就看到妳在這裡了
What the heck?
什麼跟什麼啊？
Hey, you look cute when you smile.
什麼嘛？笑起來還蠻可愛的嘛
W-What? Don't tease me!
怎樣啦？少取笑我
Be honest with yourself.
妳就誠實面對自己吧
Hey, you!
喂，你這傢伙
Don't touch my girl!
別想碰我的女人！
Huh? Who the heck are you?
啊？你算哪根蔥？
Please stop, you two!
拜託，你們兩個快住手！
Don't fight!
不要為了我打架！
Was Mild Today's story like this?!
《今甜》是這種作品嗎？
For the most part, wasn't it?
好像大部分都是這樣
The staging is good, so it's not impossible to watch,
雖然演出是不錯，不算看不下去
but there's these characters that were never in the original story.
但卻出現一堆從沒在原作出現的角色
It's probably the production's direction to use as many actors as possible.
製作方大概是想 盡可能用多一點演員吧
Uh.
啊
The flow of events wasn't like this either, right?
原作劇情也不是這樣，對吧？
When you cram 14 volumes of manga into half a season,
畢竟要把14集的漫畫塞到半季
some scenes have to be cut out.
某些場景不得不刪除呢
The acting is also…
演員的演技也…
Looks like many inexperienced actors are in it.
看來裡面有許多 演技經驗不足的演員呢
I don't know, but this is awful!
該怎麼說呢？也太慘了！
You're being too straightforward.
妳講得太直接了
I mean, wasn't Loli senpai better at acting too?
話說，蘿莉學姐 以前的演技不是更好嗎？
KARAOKE CAN
（卡拉OK館）
Shut up! She said something like that?!
吵死了！她是這樣說的嗎？
I hope she drops dead!
她給我去死啦！
Your foul mouth sure hasn't changed.
妳還是一樣嘴巴很壞耶
I'll say this for my reputation's sake,
為了我的名譽，我還是得說
but there aren't that many high schoolers who can act like me!
沒有多少高中生 能拿出像我這樣的演技好嗎？
Then why did the show turn out like that?
那為什麼這次會變成這樣？
This drama's plan is to cast as many up-and-coming models as possible
這次的網路劇是為了 盡可能推出新興的模特兒
so that it reaches the female audience who likes pretty boys.
是為了抓住女性觀眾 塞了一堆帥哥的企劃
Acting skills aren't a priority.
比起臉蛋，演技是次要的
But the title will be destroyed like that,
但這樣的話，這部戲就完蛋了
so that's why they're using me, who's known for acting, as the heroine.
所以才會採用 以演技優秀聞名的我當女主角
Considering that, wasn't your acting pretty weak?
這樣說的話 妳在裡面的演技不會太弱了點嗎？
Obviously, I'm holding back!
我當然是有所保留啊！
The rest of the cast members are all just cheesy actors!
剩下的演員全都只有三腳貓演技
Nice nails.
指甲很漂亮呢
People become stronger with people.
人需要他人扶持才能堅強
Smile for me.
為我笑一個吧
I'm the only one who can properly act in the main cast, you know?!
主演群就只剩我有像樣的演技了 你知道嗎？
What if I put on my best performance in this group?
要是我在這種情況下飆演技的話
That'll just highlight the other actors' cheesiness and it'll become a cheese fest!
只會凸顯其他人的三腳貓演技 變成三腳貓慶典了
Cheese fest?
三腳貓慶典？
I want to go all out and act too.
我也想盡全力演出啊
Who would want to go out of their way to give a poor performance?
誰會想要刻意使出蹩腳演技啊？
But, good performance and creating good work are different.
但是，出色的演技 和出色的作品是兩碼子事
It's true the seller's business scheme stands out too much in this work.
這部劇確實從企劃開始 就摻雜了太多製作方的小算盤
There's no way this can become an interesting piece.
不太可能變成多有趣的作品
When the author of the original story came to the first episode's set…
當原作者老師來到片場 看第一集的演出時…
her look of disappointment really hit me hard.
她失望的表情真的讓我很難過
But the cast and crew are each doing the best they can.
但是演員和劇組人員 全都使出渾身解數了
For the viewers and manga fans, I want to make this as good as I can.
為了觀眾和原作的粉絲 我想盡可能改善這個作品
At least I'll make it worthy of watching.
至少要讓它成為能看的作品
If it's for that, I'll even act poorly.
要是為了這個 要我展現蹩腳演技也沒問題
Even if that means hurting your reputation as an actor?
即便那樣有損妳身為演員的風評？
What's important as an actor is communication.
演員最重要的是溝通喔
Back then, I used to flaunt my acting skills.
以前的我總是誇耀自己的演技
I was certainly popular, but I never respected others.
確實成功成名了 但是卻把別人比下去了
That's why, once I had peaked, jobs disappeared in an instant.
所以一過了年紀，突然就沒工作了
"A reason to use me over children with better acting skills."
“就算別人演技比我強 別人也會想用我”
I realized that's what's important.
我發現這才是最重要的
In fact, I'm a flexible actress now,
所以現在的我是不會搶風頭
who's never stubborn, and works hard to raise the quality of work.
努力提高作品品質 讓人覺得好用的演員
Producer Kaburagi and I go way back.
製作人鏑木先生和我合作也很久了
He appointed me this time too, because I'm aware of those things.
這次也指定要用我 都是因為我懂這些原則
Since when did you learn to be so cooperative?
不知不覺就變得有協調性了呢
I am an adult now.
我可是成熟的大人了
Well, I'm sure it helps having this great face that can rival that of models!
不過，我想這張不輸給模特兒的臉蛋 也幫了不少忙吧
Actors really have nothing but self-confidence.
演員果然就是空有自信呢
And so, the filming is tomorrow! It'll be released next week!
總之，明天就要拍攝了，下週會播出
It'll be rapidly edited and rapidly delivered!
拍完後立刻剪輯，立刻送片
We'll skip the read-through, rapidly rehearse, and rapidly film!
跳過讀本，快速彩排，快速開拍！
The schedule is done for too.
行程看來也完蛋了呢
The boy of your role griped and quit, so we had to reschedule. It was a disaster.
原本演你角色的人不滿退出了 不得不重排行程，有夠慘的
Especially because it's not a great role.
畢竟不是什麼招人喜歡的角色
But that's also why I was able to squeeze you in.
不過，也是因為這樣 才能把你安插進去
Using connections and skipping the read-through.
動用人脈關係，跳過讀本
The same process again.
又是這個模式啊
When we were kids, you told me off when I did the same before.
小時候，妳就是因為這個 罵了我一頓吧？
Ah, good memories.
還真懷念呢
I never thought I'd be the one doing it now.
沒想到這次是我動用關係呢
What a dirty grown-up I've become!
我還真是變成了骯髒的大人
Quit laughing.
笑妳個頭啊？
But I can understand how the director felt now.
但我現在能理解導演的想法了
You understand why I recruited you, right?
你應該已經知道我用你的理由了吧？
I don't care how much shit anyone gives us or if they call us cheesy actors.
不管別人在背後說了什麼 或是罵我們三腳貓演員
Please, let's make this a great title together.
拜託你，和我一起創造出好的作品吧
If it's with you, I believe we can do it.
要是和你在一起，我有自信能做到
A poorly planned project with a cast that can't act.
不像樣的企劃，還有演技拙劣的演員
But after hearing her story and watching it over,
但是聽到她的情況，再重新看一遍
I can tell that the script and staging are adjusted to the cast.
看得出來劇本和分鏡 都是配合演員安排的
Even with bad acting,
就算演技拙劣
you can tell there are many techniques used to make it into something watchable.
都可以看出用了一些技巧 讓整體增加可看度
The crew is good.
有著優秀的劇組人員
And the heroine has genuine talent.
而且女主角還是幹勁十足的實力派
This may work somehow.
看來很值得一試呢
TV dramas usually have read-throughs and rehearsals indoors with the main cast,
一般來說，電視劇會和主演群 開讀本會和室內彩排
and the director lays out the storyboard off of that.
導演在這基礎上完善分鏡腳本
Normally, it's a dry run or camera rehearsal,
通常會先進行現場排演 或攝影機彩排
then a run-through, and then filming takes place on set.
然後進行預演，最後才是正式開拍
But this location could only be secured for one day,
但是這個場地只預約到一天
so the dry run to the run-through will be treated as one rehearsal.
所以只能把現場排演到預演濃縮 變成一次彩排
Practice is done only once.
練習也只能練習一次喔
What a mess. Even my director is a little more organized.
還真亂來 我家那個導演都不會那麼敷衍
There's no budget or time.
沒預算也沒時間啊
-Yo, Kana. -Hm?
-小佳奈 -嗯？
Isn't this rain awful?
今天雨也太大了吧？
I wanted them to postpone the shoot.
都想要延期拍攝了
There is a bit of leakage, but it'll be fine.
是有一點漏水，但是應該不要緊
When it's humid, my hair gets frizzy.
濕氣太重的話，髮型會變形啦
This place is so muggy and unpleasant too.
這裡溼答答的，還真不舒服
Oh, let me introduce you. This boy here is today's stalker role…
我來介紹一下 這位是今天飾演跟蹤狂的…
I'm Aqua.
我是阿奎亞
-Nice to meet… -Hi.
-很高興見到… -你好
He's got a bad attitude. I didn't even get his name.
態度還真差，連名字都沒報上來
He's the lead actor, Melt Narushima.
他是男主角，鳴嶋梅爾特
Well, he's young too,
他太年輕了
and that's common for someone who rose to fame smoothly.
平步青雲的人難免會有這種症頭
Although, I'm not one to talk…
自己說出來還真是有點受傷…
Certain idol group agencies have proper training for artists,
有一些偶像事務所 就有好好訓練旗下的偶像團體
so they're well-mannered, liked on set, and you can't go wrong with them.
有禮貌，在片場受人喜愛 總是不會錯的
There's a good reason why they're always being cast.
這也是為什麼他們總能拿到角色呢
And so, greetings are an important duty. Go on!
總之 打招呼可是很重要的工作，去吧
Nice to meet you.
初次見面
I'm Aqua from Ichigo Production. I look forward to working with you today.
我是草莓娛樂的阿奎亞 今天請您多指教
Yeah, nice to meet you.
請多指教
Masaya Kaburagi.
鏑木勝也
The man who was affiliated with Ai Hoshino somehow.
這個男人曾經和愛有某種關聯
The one who could be me and Ruby's biological father
有可能是我和露比的生父
as well as the person involved in Ai's death.
以及涉嫌害死愛的人
I need to find a chance to retrieve something that I can send for DNA testing.
得找機會拿走能做DNA鑑定的東西
That person just now is in charge of this set.
剛才那位就是片場的負責人
His thoughts are passed on to the director and then they get conveyed on set.
那個人的意見會透過導演傳達到片場
He has strong connections with model agencies,
他和模特兒事務所的關係匪淺
so this casting was mostly decided by him.
所以這次選角大權掌握在他手上
Anyway, he's obsessed with pretty faces, so that's probably why he chose you too.
總而言之，就是個顏值至上主義者 你也許也是靠臉蛋入選的
We're starting the rehearsal!
彩排開始！
Let's do this. You got the script down in your head, right?
要上囉，劇本都記在腦海裡了吧？
My role is the stalker who stalks the heroine.
我的角色是騷擾女主角的跟蹤狂
How ironic is this?
還真是諷刺
Since I'm gonna be playing a stalker just like the one who killed Ai.
居然要我演 跟殺了愛的人一樣的跟蹤狂
Ready, action!
準備，開拍！
We'll stop temporarily.
暫停一下
There's a bit of a leak here.
這裡有點漏雨啊
Then for this shot, let's increase the dolly speed and go to the next one.
這樣的話，把這鏡頭拉快一點 進到下一顆鏡頭吧
You can act properly.
你這不是演技發揮得很好嗎？
And you said you were aiming for backstage?
還說什麼想當幕後人員呢？
Anyone can do this much if they practice.
有練習的話，誰都做得到
I'm just good enough to not inconvenience others,
頂多是不造成別人困擾的程度罷了
but there's nothing appealing about me.
我自身並沒有什麼魅力
The acting Kana Arima saw that day
那一天，有馬佳奈見到我的演技
was just an abnormality caused by the contrast between my age and body.
只是因為我的精神年齡 和肉體不符的違和感產生的
Now that my body has caught up to my mental age,
如今肉體已經追上了精神年齡
I'm just an average actor found anywhere.
我不過就是隨處可見的演員罷了
If you were expecting some kind of spectacular acting, sorry.
沒發揮什麼了不起的演技 讓妳失望了吧？
I was never…
才沒有這種事…
Well, it'd be a lie if I said I wasn't expecting anything.
雖然說沒有期待是騙人的
But it's enough.
但這樣也足夠了
Your acting is like that of a person who's been practicing for a long time.
你的演技像是持續努力 從未放棄的那種演技
I like it.
我很喜歡
Your detailed techniques are thoughtful and careful.
各種不起眼的技巧 都很用心地展現出來了
It's like you're holding back your ego and adhering to the story.
就好像能抹滅自我 默默支持作品一樣
Maybe that's something unnoticeable to the average person,
或許除了長年從事演藝工作的人以外
and aside from longtime actors like us, it might not matter to everyone else.
普通人是看不出來的 對他們也無足輕重吧
Don't be so caring.
不用顧慮我的情緒
I have to be. I am the leader here after all!
當然要啊，我姑且算是主演
A lead role is a big job I haven't had in a decade, so of course I'll work hard!
我可是十年沒接過主演了 當然得好好努力一番
That's true, I haven't seen you lately, so I was surprised you were still acting.
這倒是真的，最近都沒看到妳 沒想到妳還有在演戲呢
HAVEN'T SEEN YOU LATELY
（最近都沒看到妳）
The days of my dark ages were long.
我確實沉寂了很久
I couldn't get work for so long that my career was considered dead online.
一直都接不到工作 網友都把我當過氣演員了
But I always continued my acting lessons.
但我還是繼續鑽研演技
I didn't know what I was working for anymore.
也不知道為什麼要那麼拼命
And the word "retire" crossed my mind so many times.
“引退”這個詞不停浮現在我腦海中
But!
但是
The time when my skills are acknowledged has finally come!
我的實力被認可的時刻終於到來了
I thought, "I'm really glad I continued!"
還好我堅持下來了呢
That's why, even if you didn't give a spectacular performance,
因此即便你沒有什麼了不起的演技
I was just glad to know you continued in this industry.
只要知道你留在這個業界 我就很開心了
Just knowing the fact that there was someone else struggling
知道還有人跟我一起
in this dark unforeseeable world with me.
在這只有黑暗的世界裡一起掙扎
That's enough for me.
這樣就足夠了
Can we resume the shoot?
還不能開始拍攝嗎？
Melt has a magazine photo shoot after this.
梅爾特等一下還有雜誌拍攝的行程
Almost.
快好了
Ms. Arima is keeping the cast busy, so…
演員那邊 會由有馬小姐來安撫，所以…
Kana, she's really convenient.
小佳奈就是這點很方便呢
She'll butter up anyone nicely, so it's perfect to keep her around.
不管誰都能討好 把她留在身邊真是正確
The name "Kana Arima" is known to the public after all.
“有馬佳奈”這個名號也眾所皆知
She left her agency becoming a freelancer,
離開事務所變成自由之身了
so I can use her brand value for close to no cost too.
跟這名號相比，這出場費等於免費
What a bargain.
真是划算
Well, just the part where she's fussy about acting is a pain though.
只是她一天到晚強調演技，還真囉嗦
This drama is only promotional material.
這部劇不過是用來宣傳模特兒
Acting skills aren't being demanded.
演技什麼的根本不重要
Seems like she doesn't understand that.
看來她不明白這點呢
The time when my skills are acknowledged has finally come!
我的實力被認可的時刻終於到來了
You aren't being acknowledged.
才沒有被認可呢
That's reality for you, Kana Arima.
這就是現實，有馬佳奈
It's more rare to be properly acknowledged.
得不到應得的評價才是常態
I've got the sample, so my mission's complete.
採樣也都完成了，我的任務達成了
But…
但是…
We'll resume the shoot now!
我們要開始拍攝了！
Since I am here,
既然都來了
I'll have some fun before I go home.
乾脆大鬧一場再回家吧？
Subtitle translation by: Kanami Kitabayashi
字幕翻譯：楊易